<!--
this comment is here to set appropriate whitespace above this document
proudly a collaboration between Duuckie, Bookas, and Chipbeam
-->

<Document>
# Psychologist SOP
This is the list of procedures, responsibilities, and duties of the [color=#42636d][bold]Psychologist[/bold][/color] of this station.

1. The Psychologist must treat their client without antagonizing them. Should their client become unstable, the Psychologist must immediately take action to calm their client, ending the session early if necessary. Should the Psychologist prove unable to pacify an aggressive client, the Psychologist must call [bold][color=#ba292c]Security[/color][/bold] to aid in restraining their client.

2. The Psychologist may choose to meet their client at any mutually agreed-upon location. It is recommended that this location be dimly lit, quiet, and relatively close to Medbay in the case of incident, such as at the Psychologist’s provided office. However, so long as both the Psychologist and their client are comfortable, and the area is not a specially designated secure area such as the Bridge, any location will suffice.

3. Anything said during the meeting between the Psychologist and their client is [bold]strictly confidential[/bold]. All recording devices, [bold]including Security bodycams[/bold], must be turned off unless both the Psychologist and the client mutually agree to be recorded. The Chief Medical Officer may request to sit in during therapy [bold]but is not entitled to[/bold] if the client refuses. Unless the client admits to a capital or violent crime or threatens the Psychologist (in which case Security must be notified immediately), any breach of secrecy is grounds for demotion.
<Box>A client’s Psychologist may not breach secrecy if brought onto a stand by a [color=#388c34][bold]Lawyer[/bold][/color] or interrogated by Security except for capital or violent crimes or in the Psychologist’s own case against their client.</Box>

4. The Psychologist cannot force a client to attend a meeting unless the client is ordered to by the [bold][color=#ba292c]Warden[/color][/bold], the [color=#1b67a5][bold]Head of Security[/bold][/color], the [color=#1b67a5][bold]Chief Medical Officer[/bold][/color], or the [color=#1b67a5][bold]Captain[/bold][/color].
<Box>Prisoners may request to see the Psychologist, but the Warden or the Head of Security has ultimate say on if the Psychologist will visit. It is strongly recommended that prisoners be allowed to see the Psychologist, but the privilege may be denied for especially dangerous criminals. If the Warden or Head of Security orders the Psychologist to treat prisoners, and the Chief Medical Officer or Captain approve, the Psychologist is required to treat them. The Psychologist may request additional security measures while working with prisoners, such as a secure location behind reinforced glass or an escort from Security.</Box>

5. If the client does not refuse, the Psychologist may consult the [color=#a41683][bold]Clown[/bold][/color] or the [color=#776d66][bold]Mime[/bold][/color] for their services, though neither are obliged to respond.

6. In the case that there are no personnel in need of the Psychologist’s services, the Psychologist is free to do as they would like as an Assistant would. However, should the Psychologist become needed, they must immediately return to their role as expected.

7. The Psychologist is [bold]not[/bold] entitled to freely operate on and administer medicine to patients, with the exception of administering Psicodine (though the Psychologist may freely make recommendations regarding mental health and wellbeing). If the Psychologist wishes to act as qualified Medical staff in Medbay, they must ask for the permission of the Chief Medical Officer and should have MedTek installed onto their PDA. While working as Medical staff, the Psychologist must adhere to the appropriate SOP for the role they assume.

8. The Psychologist must receive approval from a [color=#42636d][bold]Medical Doctor[/bold][/color] or the Chief Medical Officer to prescribe narcotics to a client.

</Document>
