<!--
this comment is here to set appropriate whitespace above this document
proudly a collaboration between Duuckie, Bookas, and Chipbeam
-->

<Document>
# Virologist SOP
This is the list of procedures, responsibilities, and duties of the [color=#42636d][bold]Virologist[/bold][/color] of this station.

1. The Virologist is expected to fulfill the duties of regular [color=#42636d][bold]Medical Doctors[/bold][/color] if there are no active Medical Doctors/Interns and there is no ongoing Viral Outbreak.

2. The Virologist must wear a Sterile Mask or internals, Latex/Nitrile Gloves, and a Bio Suit and Bio Hood while working in Virology. The mask must cover the Virologist’s face. Virologists are not permitted to eat or drink inside Virology.
<Box>It is the responsibility of the Virologist to ensure that they do not fall ill in their own line of work. Wear PPE.</Box>

  3. The Virologist is not permitted to release [bold]any[/bold] virus into the station without permission of the [color=#1b67a5][bold]Chief Medical Officer[/bold][/color] If the Chief Medical Officer is absent, then the [color=#1b67a5][bold]Captain[/bold][/color] must give permission. Viruses slated to be released must include a full list of symptoms, and a vaccine of the virus must be on hand to be given out on request.
  <Box>The virus may not have any harmful symptoms whatsoever unless the benefits of the virus neutralize the symptoms. Neutral or harmless symptoms are permitted. Intentional release of a harmful virus into the station may include punishment up to and including death. The Virologist who releases a harmful virus is criminally responsible for the personnel who are injured and die from it.</Box>

4. During a Viral Outbreak, the Virologist must direct (or ask other Medical staff to direct) infected personnel to Virology. Infected personnel must remain quarantined in Virology, and they must immediately leave Virology once cured. Virologists are not permitted to leave Virology or Medbay except to travel between the two.

5. The Virologist must place anyone who dies of disease in Quarantine into a body bag or freezer until the disease subsides. The body must then be transferred to a Medical Doctor for treatment and revival. Virologists are not permitted to intentionally cause patients to die.
<Box>In extreme overload, the Morgue and/or Cryo Pods (or alternatives) may be used for preservation, but corpses should be checked for [bold][italic]souls[/italic][/bold] to ensure they can be revived.</Box>

6. The Virologist must maintain the entirety of Virology in a hygienic state. This includes (but is not limited to) cleaning organic residue, fluids, and/or corpses.
<Box>Janitorial Services should be requested for major spills if there is no ongoing Viral Outbreak and there is no active, dangerous virus that would pose a threat to Janitorial Services.</Box>

7. The Virologist must recycle the biomass of deceased test subjects in a timely manner both to ensure cleanliness and to ensure that Cloning is stocked with at least 100 units of Biomass at any given time. Additional Biomass may be stored in a Medical Biofabricator until needed.<!-- the virologist deals with monkeys so it’s only fair that they contribute biomass
--></Document>
